{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following statements is not correct?", "opta": "log10 10 = 1", "optb": "log (2 + 3) = log (2 x 3)", "optc": "log10 1 = 0", "optd": "log (1 + 2 + 3) = log 1 + log 2 + log 3", "ans": "B", "explanation": "(a) Since loga a = 1, so log10 10 = 1.\n(b) log (2 + 3) = log 5 and log (2 x 3) = log 6 = log 2 + log 3\n\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 log (2 + 3)  log (2 x 3)\n(c) Since loga 1 = 0, so log10 1 = 0.\n(d) log (1 + 2 + 3) = log 6 = log (1 x 2 x 3) = log 1 + log 2 + log 3.\nSo, (b) is incorrect."}, {"question": "If log 2 = 0.3010 and log 3 = 0.4771, the value of log5 512 is:", "opta": "2.870", "optb": "2.967", "optc": "3.876", "optd": "3.912", "ans": "C", "explanation": "log5 512\n\n\n\n=\nlog 512\n\n\nlog 5\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n=\nlog 29\n\n\nlog (10/2)\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n=\n9 log 2\n\n\nlog 10 - log 2\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n=\n(9 x 0.3010)\n\n\n1 - 0.3010\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n=\n2.709\n\n\n0.699\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n=\n2709\n\n\n699\n\n\n\n\n\n\n= 3.876"}, {"question": "log 8\nis equal to:\n\n\nlog 8", "opta": "1\n\n\n8", "optb": "8", "ans": "C", "explanation": "log 8\n=\nlog (8)1/2\n=\nlog 8\n=\n1\n.\n\n\nlog 8\nlog 8\nlog 8\n2"}, {"question": "If log 27 = 1.431, then the value of log 9 is:", "opta": "0.934", "optb": "0.945", "optc": "0.954", "optd": "0.958", "ans": "C", "explanation": "log 27 = 1.431\n log (33 ) = 1.431\n 3 log 3 = 1.431\n log 3 = 0.477\n log 9 = log(32 ) = 2 log 3 = (2 x 0.477) = 0.954."}, {"question": "If log\na\n+\nlog\nb\n= log (a + b), then:\n\n\nb\na", "opta": "a + b = 1", "optb": "a - b = 1", "optc": "a = b", "optd": "a2 - b2 = 1", "ans": "A", "explanation": "log\na\n+ log\nb\n= log (a + b)\n\n\nb\na\n\n\n\n\n\n\n log (a + b) = log\n\na\nx\nb\n\n= log 1.\n\n\nb\na\n\n\n\nSo, a + b = 1."}, {"question": "If log10 7 = a, then log10\n\n1\n\nis equal to:\n\n\n70", "opta": "- (1 + a)", "optb": "(1 + a)-1", "ans": "A", "explanation": "log10\n\n1\n\n\n\n70\n\n\n\n= log10 1 - log10 70\n\n\n\n= - log10 (7 x 10)\n\n\n\n= - (log10 7 + log10 10)\n\n\n\n= - (a + 1)."}, {"question": "If log10 2 = 0.3010, then log2 10 is equal to:", "opta": "699\n\n\n301", "optb": "301", "ans": "B", "explanation": "log2 10 =\n1\n=\n1\n=\n10000\n=\n1000\n.\n\n\nlog10 2\n0.3010\n3010\n301"}, {"question": "If log10 2 = 0.3010, the value of log10 80 is:", "opta": "1.6020", "optb": "1.9030", "optc": "3.9030", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "log10\u00a080\n= log10 (8 x 10)\n\n\n\n= log10 8 + log10 10\n\n\n\n= log10 (23 ) + 1\n\n\n\n= 3 log10 2 + 1\n\n\n\n= (3 x 0.3010) + 1\n\n\n\n= 1.9030."}, {"question": "If log10 5 + log10 (5x + 1) = log10 (x + 5) + 1, then x is equal to:", "opta": "1", "optb": "3", "optc": "5", "optd": "10", "ans": "B", "explanation": "log10 5 + log10 (5x + 1) = log10 (x + 5) + 1\n log10 5 + log10 (5x + 1) = log10 (x + 5) + log10 10\n log10  [5 (5x + 1)] = log10 [10(x + 5)]\n 5(5x + 1) = 10(x + 5)\n 5x + 1 = 2x + 10\n 3x = 9\n x = 3."}, {"question": "The value of\n\n1\n+\n1\n+\n1\n\nis:\n\n\nlog3 60\nlog4 60\nlog5 60", "opta": "0", "optb": "1", "optc": "5", "optd": "60", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Given expression\n= log60 3 + log60 4 + log60 5\n\n\n\n= log60 (3 x 4 x 5)\n\n\n\n= log60 60\n\n\n\n= 1."}, {"question": "If log 2 = 0.30103, the number of digits in 264 is:", "opta": "18", "optb": "19", "optc": "20", "optd": "21", "ans": "C", "explanation": "log (264)\n= 64 x log 2\n\n\n\n= (64 x 0.30103)\n\n\n\n= 19.26592\n\n\n\nIts characteristic is 19.\nHence, then number of digits in 264 is 20."}, {"question": "If logx\n\n9\n\n= -\n1\n, then x is equal to:\n\n\n16\n2", "opta": "-\n3\n\n\n4", "optb": "3", "ans": "D", "explanation": "logx\n\n9\n\n= -\n1\n\n\n16\n2\n\n\n\n\n\n\n x-1/2\n=\n9\n\n\n16\n\n\n\n\n\n\n \n1\n=\n9\n\n\nx\n16\n\n\n\n\n\n\n x =\n16\n\n\n9\n\n\n\n\n\n\n x =\n\n16\n\n2\n\n\n9\n\n\n\n\n\n\n x =\n256\n\n\n81"}, {"question": "If ax = by, then:", "opta": "log\na\n=\nx\n\n\nb\ny", "optb": "a", "ans": "C", "explanation": "ax = by\n log ax = log by\n x log a = y log b\n\n\n\n \nlog a\n=\ny\n.\n\n\nlog b\nx"}, {"question": "If logx y = 100 and log2 x = 10, then the value of y is:", "opta": "210", "optb": "2100", "optc": "21000", "optd": "210000", "ans": "C", "explanation": "log 2 x = 10 \u00a0 \u00a0  \u00a0 \u00a0 x = 210.\n logx y = 100\n y = x100\n y = (210)100 \u00a0 \u00a0 [put value of x]\n y = 21000."}, {"question": "The value of log2 16 is:", "opta": "1\n\n\n8", "optb": "8", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Let log2 16 = n.\nThen, 2n = 16 = 24 \u00a0 \u00a0  \u00a0 \u00a0 n = 4.\n log2 16 = 4."}]]}